arturia.com 2019-12-19

# Arturia - Privacy policy

_Last revised: September 25, 2019_

At Arturia, we care about your privacy. For this reason, we collect and use personal data only as it might be needed to help us deliver our services to you. We also need information about you when you use our softwares and our licensing software, Arturia Software Center ("ASC").

Personal data is defined by the General Data Protection Regulation (EU Regulation 2016/679 modifying the Act n°78-17 of 6 January 1978 on information technology, data files and civil liberties) (the “GDPR”) as ‘any information relating to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified in particular by reference to an identifier’. Personal data is, in simpler terms, any information about you that enables you to be identified. Personal data covers obvious information such as your name and contact details, but it also covers less obvious information such as identification numbers, electronic location data, and other online identifiers.

Our Privacy Policy is intended to describe to you how and what data we collect, and how and why we use your personal data. It also describes options we provide for you to access, update or otherwise take control of your personal data that we process.

## 1\. Information About Arturia

Arturia, société par actions simplifiée having its registered located 26, avenue Jean Kuntzmann 38330 Montbonnot Saint Martin, registrered at the Grenoble RCS under n° 423 302 421 [VAT number: FR56423302421.]

If at any time you have questions about our practices or any of your rights described below, you may reach our dedicated team by contacting us at [privacy-inquiries@arturia.com](mailto:privacy-inquiries@arturia.com). This inbox is actively monitored and managed so that we can deliver an experience that you can confidently trust.

Likewise, we’ve also created a [Privacy Center](https://www.arturia.com/support/privacycenter) to provide answers to your most common questions, quick links to access your MyArturia settings, instructions on how to exercise certain rights that might be available to you, and the list of third parties and partners we may share some of your personal data.

Your acceptance of this Privacy Policy is deemed to occur upon your first use of our Site. You will also be required to read and accept this Privacy Policy when signing up for an account or purchasing any of our products or services. If you do not accept and agree with this Privacy Policy, you must stop using Site immediately.

## 2\. What Personal Data do we collect?

We collect information so that we can provide the best possible experience when you use our services. Much of the mandatory personal data, usually indicated with an asterisk (the symbol *) is collected directly from you when you:

  * Purchase any of our services (ex: billing information, including first and last name, address, phone number in case of physical purchases)
  * Create an account (first and last name, email address, country)
  * Register a product (serial number and unlock code of the product)
  * Request assistance from our support team (first and last name, email address, phone number)
  * Complete contact forms or request newsletters or other information from us (first and last name, email address)
  * Participate in contests and surveys, apply for a job, or otherwise participate in activities we promote that might require information about you.

When participating in any of these activities, other optional information may be asked of you. Any data input not followed by an asterisk is optional. If you do not wish to provide us with this information, you are free to leave the field blank. We also collect additional information when delivering our services to you to ensure necessary and optimal performance. These methods of collection may not be as obvious to you, so we wanted to highlight and explain what these might be, as they vary from time to time, and how they work. These methods are detailed below:

**Account related information** is collected in association with your use of our services, such as purchases, data linked to registration, transfer, activation and deactivation, be it online or offline of our products through the means of the Arturia Software Center. This usage data can be shared with other Arturia services, such as information requests, customer service requests, and notes or details explaining what you asked for and how we responded.

**Data from the Arturia Software Center (ASC)** is collected in order to permit the use of our software. This mandatory data includes the used device name, its OS, CPU and RAM information, IP address and a custom unique identifier. The Arturia Software Center lets you optionally share usage information of our services. If you choose to accept this, it may send us the usage frequency of the Arturia licensed software titles activated on the machine, the version of the software titles and the Digital Audio Workstation ("DAW") in which you use it. This information lets us tailor our services to match our customers needs, so that you receive the best experience possible.

## 3\. How we utilize Personal Data

Under the GDPR, we must always have a lawful basis for using personal data. This may be because the data is necessary for our performance of a contract with you, because you have consented to our use of your personal data, or because it is in our legitimate business interests to use it. We strongly believe in both minimizing the data we collect.

Arturia may use your personal data for the following purposes:

Delivering, improving, updating and enhancing the Services we provide to you.

We may use your personal data for the following purposes:

  * Providing and managing your account.
  * Supplying our products and services and provide customer relationship service.
  * Payment of your orders. Personalize, improve and optimize the operation and performance of our services (again, including our websites) and how we interact with your targeted emails.
  * Diagnose problems with, and identify any security risks, errors, or required enhancements to the services we provide.
  * Detect and prevent fraud and abuse of our services and systems.
  * Collect aggregate statistics about use of the services. This information is not linked with any one personal account, but could be considered “personal data”, so we treat it accordingly.
  * Understand and analyze how you use our services and what products and services are most relevant to you, if you allow us to do so within the Arturia Software Center.

### Sharing with trusted third parties

We may share your personal data with trusted third party service providers as necessary for them to perform services on our behalf and/or when you have permitted such use (where applicable), such as:

  * Processing payments
  * Physically shipping services to you
  * Serving advertisements
  * Conducting contests or surveys
  * Performing analysis of our services and customer demographics
  * Communicating with you, such as by way email or survey delivery
  * Customer relationship management.

We only share the minimal personal data necessary for any third party to provide the services as requested or as needed on our behalf. These third parties and any subcontractors are subject to strict data processing terms and conditions and are - without your consent - prohibited from utilizing, sharing or retaining your personal data for any purpose other than as they have been specifically contracted for.

### Communicating with you

We may contact you directly regarding products or services you have purchased from us, where it may be necessary to deliver transactional or service related communications. We may also contact you through a third party service provider with offers for additional services we think you’ll find valuable if you give us consent, or where allowed based upon legitimate interests. You don’t need to provide consent as a condition to purchase our goods or services. These contacts are currently limited to emails.

You may also update your subscription preferences with respect to receiving communications from us and/or our partners by signing into your [MyArturia account](https://www.arturia.com/myarturia), and hitting the “Edit” button in the “My Login Info” section under the “My Account” heading.

### Transfer of personal data abroad

Currently, all our servers that may store personal data are located in France. Some of our services providers may need some of this personal data in order to ensure their service, and they may store personal data outside of France, or outside of the European Economic Area (the “EEA” consists of all EU member states, plus Norway, Iceland, and Liechtenstein). In these cases, your personal data is handled according to the Privacy Shield Framework, or in accordance with standard contractual clauses for the transfer of personal data to processors established in third countries as edicted by the European Commission signed between Arturia and the service provider. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List.

For your peace of mind, you may wish to learn how companies we share data with utilize your information, and comply with the GDPR. The list of companies we partner with can be found in our [Privacy Center](https://www.arturia.com/support/privacycenter).

Arturia is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Arturia complies with the General Data Protection Regulation for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, including onward transfer liability provisions.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed to your satisfaction, please contact us.

### Compliance with legal, regulatory and law enforcement requests

We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We will disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal process (such as subpoena requests), to protect our property and rights, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we consider to be illegal or unethical.

To the extent we are legally permitted to do so, we will take reasonable steps to notify you in the event that we are required to provide your personal information to third parties as part of legal process.

### Targeted advertisements

Targeted ads or interest-based offers may be presented to you based on your activities on our webpages, and other websites, and based on the products you currently own. These offers will display as varying product banners presented to you while browsing. We also partner with third parties to manage our advertising on our webpages and other websites. Our third party partners may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about such activities in order to provide you with advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests, and to measure advertising effectiveness, subject to the conditions detailed in Part 4.

If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising, please contact us at : [privacy-inquiries@arturia.com](mailto:privacy-inquiries@arturia.com).

### Third-party websites

Our websites may contain links to third-party websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of third-party websites we refer to. Please read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

## 4\. Use of Cookies

Our site may place and access certain first-party Cookies on your computer or device. First-party Cookies are those placed directly by us and are used only by us.

Cookies and similar technologies on our websites allow us to track your browsing behavior, links clicked, items purchased, your device type, and to collect various data, including analytics, about how you use and interact with our services. This lets us provide you with more relevant product offerings, a better experience on our sites, and to collect, analyze and improve the performance of our services. We may also collect location and system data in the form of your IP address, metadata, log files, and cookie/device IDs when you access our services so that we can personalize our service to you.

This information includes specific data about your interactions with the features, content and links contained within the services, including browser name and version, the date and time the services were used, the type of device used to access the services, the name you defined for it, what operating system is used, custom unique device identifiers and error data. Some of this data collected might be capable of and be used to approximate your location.

Certain features of our Site depend on Cookies to function. Cookie Law deems these Cookies to be “strictly necessary”. These Cookies are shown in the table below. Your consent will not be sought to place these Cookies, but it is still important that you are aware of them. You may still block these Cookies by changing your internet browser’s settings as detailed below, but please be aware that our Site may not work properly if you do so. We have taken great care to ensure that your privacy is not at risk by allowing them.

The following first-party Cookies may be placed on your computer or device:

Name of Cookie | Purpose | Strictly Necessary  
---|---|---  
joomla_user_state | CMS Technical Cookie | Yes  
aa74d0159c45485e7030c483e256bb7e | CMS Technical Cookie | Yes  
  
### Website analytics

We use multiple web analytics tools provided by service partners such as Google Analytics or Facebook to collect information about how you interact with our website, including what pages you visit, what site you visited prior to visiting our website, how much time you spend on each page, what operating system and web browser you use, and network and IP information. We use the information provided by these tools to improve our services. These tools place cookies in your browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit our website. Each cookie cannot be used by anyone other than the service provider, Google for Google Analytics, for example.

The information collected from the cookie may be transmitted to and stored by these service partners on servers in a country other than the country in which you reside. Though information collected does not include personal data such as name, address, or billing information, the information collected is used and shared by these service providers in accordance with their individual privacy policies.

The analytics service(s) used by our website use(s) the following Cookies:

Name of Cookie | First / Third Party | Provider | Purpose  
---|---|---|---  
_ga, _gat, _gid, AMP_TOKEN | First Party | Google Analytics | • Distinguish unique users   
• Throttle the request rate  
__utma, __utmt, __utmb, __utmc, __utmz, __utmv | First Party | Google Analytics | • Determine which domain to measure   
• Distinguish unique users  
• Throttle the request rate  
• Remember the number and time of previous visits  
• Remember traffic source information  
• Determine the start and end of a session  
• Remember the value of visitor-level custom variables  
criteo_write_test | First Party | Criteo | Setup unique visitor identifier across visits and devices  
cto_lwid, cto_bundle | First Party | Criteo | Collects visitor behavior to display more relevant ads  
ajs_anonymous_id | First Party | Segment | Help counting website visitors  
ajs_group_id | First Party | Segment | Help identify visitor usage and events on the website – does not collect data.  
ajs_user_id | First Party | Segment | Collects information regarding your usage of the website  
_fbp | First Party | Facebook | Used to provide better targeted ads  
_hjid | First Party | Hotjar | Unique identifier for HotJar, used to identify visitors main focus points on the website  
__cfduid | First Party | CloudFlare | Helps detecting malicious users to avoid DDoS attacks  
  
You can control the technologies we use by managing your settings through our Cookie Policy or the ‘cookie banners” that may be presented, depending on URL of website visited, when you first visit our web pages. You may also control these settings by using third party privacy tools such as Disconnect, Ghostery, and others.

You can choose to delete Cookies on your computer or device at any time, however you may lose any information that enables you to access Our Site more quickly and efficiently including, but not limited to, login and personalisation settings.

It is recommended that you keep your internet browser and operating system up-to-date and that you consult the help and guidance provided by the developer of your internet browser and manufacturer of your computer or device if you are unsure about adjusting your privacy settings.

## 5\. How you can access, update your data

To easily access, view, update your personal data - where available - or to update your subscription preferences, please sign into your [MyArturia account](https://www.arturia.com/myarturia) on the Arturia website.

If you want to know what personal data we may have on you, please contact [privacy-inquiries@arturia.com](mailto:privacy-inquiries@arturia.com) for details of that personal data and for a copy of it (where any such personal data is held). This is known as a “subject access request”.

All subject access requests should be made in writing and sent to the above email. There is not normally any charge for a subject access request. If your request is ‘manifestly unfounded or excessive’ (for example, if you make repetitive requests) a fee may be charged to cover our administrative costs in responding.

We will respond to your subject access request within one month of receiving it. Normally, we aim to provide a complete response, including a copy of your personal data within that time. In some cases, however, particularly if your request is more complex, more time may be required up to a maximum of three months from the date we receive your request. You will be kept fully informed of our progress. If you make a request to delete your personal data and that data is necessary for the products or services you have purchased, the request will be honored only to the extent it is no longer necessary for any services purchased or required for our legitimate business purposes or legal or contractual record keeping requirements.

If you are unable for any reason to access your [MyArturia accounth](http://www.arturia.com/myarturia), you may send an email at [privacy-inquiries@arturia.com](mailto:privacy-inquiries@arturia.com).

## 6\. How we secure, store and retain your data

We follow generally accepted standards to store and protect the personal data we collect. This applies to when data is transmitted, received, and stored, and includes the use of encryption where appropriate.

We retain personal data only for as long as necessary to provide the services you have requested and thereafter for a variety of legitimate legal or business purposes.

These might include retention periods:

  * mandated by law, contract or similar obligations applicable to our business operations;
  * for preserving, resolving, defending or enforcing our legal/contractual rights; or
  * needed to maintain adequate and accurate business and financial records.

If you have any questions about the security or retention of your personal data, you can contact us at [privacy-inquiries@arturia.com](mailto:privacy-inquiries@arturia.com).

## 7\. Age restrictions.

Arturia does not knowingly collect or use personal information from children. We encourage parents and legal guardians to monitor their children’s internet usage and to help enforce this privacy policy by instructing their children never to provide personal information without their permission.

## 8\. Changes in our Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy and any other places we deem appropriate, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page, at least thirty (30) days prior to the implementation of the changes.

## 9\. What Are My Rights?

Under the GDPR, you have the following rights, which we will always work to uphold:

  * The right to be informed about our collection and use of your personal data. This Privacy policy should tell you everything you need to know, but you can always contact us to find out more or to ask any questions using the details in Part 10.
  * The right to access the personal data we hold about you.
  * The right to have your personal data rectified if any of your personal data held by us is inaccurate or incomplete.
  * The right to be forgotten, i.e. the right to ask us to delete or otherwise dispose of any of your personal data that we have.
  * The right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data.
  * The right to object to us using your personal data for a particular purpose or purposes.
  * The right to data portability. This means that, if you have provided personal data to us directly, we are using it with your consent or for the performance of a contract, and that data is processed using automated means, you can ask us a copy of that personal data to re-use with another service or business in many cases.
  * Rights relating to automated decision-making and profiling.

For more information about our use of your personal data or exercising your rights as outlined above, please contact us at [privacy-inquiries@arturia.com](mailto:privacy-inquiries@arturia.com). Further information about your rights can also be obtained from the Commission de l’Informatique et des libertés (CNIL).

If you have any cause for complaint about our use of your personal data, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the CNIL.

If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about our Privacy Policy, our practices or our services, you may contact our Office at [privacy-inquiries@arturia.com](mailto:privacy-inquiries@arturia.com).

_Copyright © 2019 Arturia All rights reserved._
